# **Brett Stokes**

bstokes0971@gmail.com | 210-387-3054 | https://www.brett-stokes.com/ | https://www.linkedin.com/in/brett-stokes/

# PROFILE SUMMARY

Data Analyst who specializes in Data Visualization, Database Management, Machine Learning, and Web Development. Proficient with Python, SQL, and Tableau. Dedicated professional with engineering experience in upstream oil and gas operations. Effective team player with excellent communication, organizational, and leadership skills.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**Halliburton Energy Services** 

Rock Springs, Wyoming, U.S.

Field Engineer - Frac/Acid

Apr 2018 - Nov 2019

- Executed data acquisition for entire operation, performed real time well site data analysis, and tailored fracture treatment accordingly based on resources and customers needs
- Performed Laboratory QA/QC prior to every job and during operations to ensure adequate fluid viscosity for ideal proppant delivery and fracture propagation
- Delivered timely Post Job Reports to customer that included summary of treatment, total inventory pumped, and visualizations for each stage of operation.
- Familiar with slickwater, gel, acid, CO2, and N2 stimulation operations in multiple formations around the nation.

Halliburton Energy Services

Williston, North Dakota, U.S.

# Assistant Operator - Frac/Acid

Sep 2017 - Mar 2018

- Performed pre and post job inspections, performed and completed preventative maintenance procedures, and maintained support equipment necessary for operation.
- Maintained smooth operation of stimulation processes in various roles: proppant delivery, chemical delivery, blender and ADP operation, and valve operation in high pressure zones.
- Developed proficiency rigging up / rigging down fracturing equipment to suit customer needs in several onsite operations with various E&P companies.
- Practiced safe driving procedures while driving equipment to and from locations.
- Adhered to all HSE procedures and guidelines, and all other appropriate safety and service quality protocols and guidelines while ensuring customer satisfaction.

# **EDUCATION**

UNIVERSITY OF TEXAS AT SAN ANTONIO

San Antonio, Texas, U.S.

# M.S. in Data Analytics

2020 - 2021

Coursework: DA Tools and Techniques, Data Visualization, Data Driven Decision Making, DA Marketing Analytics

# **Projects:**

- Bitcoin Price Forecast Graph A visualization in tableau forecasting the price of bitcoin for 2023 based on historical prices
- Small Business Owners Visualization A series of visualizations examining data and trends among Small Business Owners in the US.

# **TEXAS TECH UNIVERSITY**

Lubbock, Texas, U.S.

### **B.S.** in Petroleum Engineering

2012 - 2016

Coursework: Reservoir Engineering, Petroleum Design, Formation Evaluation, Petroleum Geology, Calculus 1-3, Physics 1-2, Statics, Dynamics, Solids, Fluids, Thermodynamics, Linear Algebra

# **Projects:**

 Senior Design - Created an estimate for OOIP for a real formation based on rock and fluid properties gathered through logging analysis. Developed a plan for drilling and completing a well including all cost estimates and potential revenue.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Programming Languages: Python, R, SQL, Java, SAS

Tools: Scikit-Learn, NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Tableau, MS Excel, OpenCV, Keras,

Tensorflow Database Management Systems: MySQL, SQLite, PostgreSQL

Internet Technologies: Flask, HTML5, CSS